We all need to eat, and when we go to buy food at the supermarket, we’re spoilt for choice in the range of items available that can be turned into a delicious meal.
我们都需要进食，当去超市采购食物时，我们总会很难选择那些琳琅满目的食材，它们都能被做成美味的饭菜。
But we often purchase food that’s been mass-produced and that’s travelled many miles before it ends up on our plate.
但我们购买的食物往往都是大规模生产的，在端上我们餐桌前，已经经过了长途运输。
So for some, growing their own food is a better option – and it tastes good too!
因此对有些人来说，自己种植食物是更好的选择——而且这样种出来的食物味道也很不错！
From growing vegetables in little pots on your balcony to tending to a small plot of land, called allotments, there are many ways to produce home-grown food.
从在阳台的小盆里种蔬菜，到打理一小块被称为租用地的土地，自己种植食材的方式有很多种。
Allotments are a typically British idea, and they give people with a small or no garden, a space to plant and nurture fruit and vegetables.
租用地是颇具英国特色的产物，它能给那些花园面积小或者根本没有花园的人，提供一块种植和培育蔬果的场地。
It can be backbreaking work digging, weeding and watering the soil, but the result is fresh, organically grown produce, contributing to our ‘five-a-day’ diet.
翻土、除草、浇水这些活儿虽然繁重累人，但收获的是新鲜的有机蔬果，能助力我们实现“每天五种蔬果”的健康饮食目标。
The recent Covid-19 pandemic lockdown means demand for allotments has seen a renaissance.
最近新冠疫情的封锁措施，让人们对租用地的需求迎来了一次复兴。
Miriam Dobson from the University of Sheffield told the BBC that people with allotments have been spending a lot of their time on their plots, growing plenty of fresh fruit and veg – which, at times, have been challenging to source in supermarkets.
谢菲尔德大学的米里亚姆·多布森向英国广播公司表示，拥有租用地的人们在自家地块上投入了大量时间，种出了很多新鲜蔬果——而这些蔬果有时在超市里是很难买到的。她指出：“新冠疫情……
She says “Coronavirus has… highlighted to people the fragility inherent within our globalised food system.
让人们意识到我们全球化食品体系内在的脆弱性。
In a time of crisis, interest in self-sufficiency rises.”
在危机时期，人们对自给自足的兴趣会日益高涨。”
But for those with limited space, a solution to grow your own veg lies closer to home – using pots.
但对于空间有限的人来说，在家种植蔬菜的解决办法其实很简单——用花盆就行。
Once you can lay your hands on some compost, you can plant seeds.
只要能弄到一些堆肥，就可以播种了。
Sheila Brand lives in a third-floor flat in Rotterdam. She has managed to grow tomatoes and aubergines and is already harvesting raspberries.
希拉·布兰德住在鹿特丹一栋公寓的三楼，她成功种出了番茄和茄子，现在已经开始采收树莓了。
She told the BBC watching the plants grow “is very exciting: 'Oh it's got a new leaf!' ”
她向英国广播公司表示，看着植物生长的过程“非常令人兴奋：‘哇，它又长出一片新叶子啦！’”
As well as the benefits of saving money and enjoying tasty food, gardener Mark Ridsdill-Smith says “growing your own from a balcony or window ledge not only improves your wellbeing and immediate environment, you can actually grow a lot of veg.”
除了省钱和享用美味食物这些好处外，园丁马克·里兹迪尔-史密斯表示：“在阳台或窗台上自己种植蔬果，不仅能改善身心健康和周边环境，实际上还能收获不少蔬菜呢。”
So, maybe it’s time for us all to get planting and develop our green fingers!
所以，或许现在正是我们开始播种，培养自己园艺天赋的时候了！